<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi I'm Brandon</title><link>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Hi I'm Brandon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 20:27:55 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GOtchas Part 1</title><link>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/go-tidbits-gotchas-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 20:27:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/go-tidbits-gotchas-1/</guid><description>In order for me to build the habit of posting weekly content, hopefully every sunday, I would need to reduce the scope of what I will be sharing. Hopefully this reduction in scope will make me motivated habitually of post useful software engineering content.
One of the common gotchas in GO relates to the use of slices. In gist a slice is a dynamically sized array. Within the concrete implementation of a slice are 3 fields:</description></item><item><title>GO Tidbits Antipattern Part 1</title><link>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/go-tidbits-anti-patterns-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 16:14:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/go-tidbits-anti-patterns-1/</guid><description>Many engineers that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across in my journey often mention that software engineering is a craft. When I read engineering books such as Code Complete, the concept of craftmenship and the gathering of &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; for the &amp;ldquo;toolbox&amp;rdquo; were highlighted several times. That got me curious on what sort of &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; I could gather.
In software engineering there is the concept of design patterns. These patterns. broadly speaking, are commonly used solutions to tackle problem spaces that they were design for.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 14:33:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world, I am starting my first step into posting on this webpage. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to share learnings on engineering ideas ranging from code to system design using this platform on a weekly basis.
I figured that posting like this would keep myself accountable for my own growth and internalise concepts better. I suppose another good side effect would be racking my brain to desseminate information in a logical and coherent way (it&amp;rsquo;s been too long).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 18:41:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://brandonyeoxg.github.io/about/</guid><description>Backend software engineer at Grab with over two years of experience building scalable distributed systems on the cloud.
Designed and implemented platform features for the subscriptions and fulfilment services in Grab that is used by over 2.5 million consumers daily.
What excites me is the challenge of working in large scale complex Service Oriented Architecuture (SOA) systems. While taking pride in maintaining code quality through SOLID principles on the code level and system design quality through using thought out patterns like event driven architecture using message queues.</description></item></channel></rss>